Choose life.
Trainspotting is a drama, crime film directed by Danny Boyle.
Heroin addict Mark Renton stumbles through bad ideas and sobriety attempts
with his unreliable friends --Sick Boy, Begbie, Spud and Tommy.
He also has an underage girlfriend, Diane, along for the ride.
After cleaning up and moving from Edinburgh to London, Mark finds he can't
escape the life he left behind as Begbie and Sick Boy come knocking.
Renton, played by Ewan McGregor.
Spud, played by Ewen Bremner.
Sick Boy, played by Jonny Lee Miller.
Tommy, played by Kevin McKidd.
Begbie, played by Robert Carlyle.
Diane, played by Kelly Macdonald.
Trainspotting is a 1996 British crime black comedy drama film directed by Danny Boyle, and starring Ewan McGregor,
Ewen Bremner, Jonny Lee Miller, Kevin McKidd, Robert Carlyle and Kelly Macdonald in her film debut.
It is written in English and Scots.
Based on the 1993 novel by Irvine Welsh, the film was
released in the United Kingdom on 23 February 1996.
The film follows a group of heroin addicts in an economically
depressed area of Edinburgh and their passage through life.
Beyond drug addiction, other themes in the film include an
exploration of urban poverty and squalor in Edinburgh.
Trainspotting was released to critical acclaim, and is regarded by
many critics as one of the best films of the 1990s.
The film was ranked tenth by the British Film Institute (BFI) in its
list of Top 100 British films of the 20th century.
In 2004, the film was voted the best Scottish film of
all time in a general public poll.
A 2017 poll, which consisted of 150 actors, directors, writers, producers and critics
for Time Out magazine, ranked it the tenth best British film ever.
A sequel, T2 Trainspotting, was released in January 2017,
with TriStar Pictures distributing it.
The film explores themes of drug dealer, friendship, london,
england, based on novel or book, scotland.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and emotional.